(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T18:13:28.444610",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんなこんばんは
Good evening, everyone!
ストレイライトの黛冬優子です
I'm Fuyuko Mayuzumi from Straylight.
みんな冬って呼んでね
Everyone, call me Fuyu!
そしてくっくっく
And... heh, heh, heh,
リトルデーモン達ごきげんよう
greetings, Little Demons.
私はヨハネ
I am Yohane,
美しさのあまり天界を追放された堕天使、ということで
a fallen angel banished from heaven for my supreme beauty. So,
この番組はあした9日(土)あさって10日(日)異次元フェス アイドルマスター★ラブライブ!歌合戦in東京ドームを
this program commemorates the Jigen Fes Idolmaster & Love Live! Utagassen in Tokyo Dome,
記念した音楽番組です
held on Saturday the 9th and Sunday the 10th!
一緒に宣伝隊長を務める津島善子ちゃんと
Together with Tsushima Yoshiko-chan,
お送りします
we bring you this show—
よし子じゃなくてヨハネね
It's Yoshiko, not Yohane!
それに冬優子？
And Fuyu-ko?
今日は私たち二人だけじゃなくて超強力な助っ人が来ていのよね
Today, we don't just have the two of us, we have a super powerful helper coming, right?
はい！
Yes!
今日は冬優子達と一緒にこの番組を盛り上げてくれる素敵なアンバサダーをゲストにお呼びしています
Today, we've invited wonderful ambassadors to guest-star and help liven up this program with Fuyu and the others!
かつもくせよ
Behold!
我が輩のお名前はラプラス・ダークネスだ
My name is Laplace Darkness!
今日は冬優子を応援しに来たぞ
I've come to cheer for Fuyu today!
よー！にげどもー！ラブライブ！アンバサダーどーらじゃよーん
Hey, you guys! I'm Dora, the Love Live! Ambassador!
ドレイクはヨハネを応援しに来ました！
Drake has come to cheer for Yohane!
と言うわけで冬優子と私のスケットとしてそれぞれ来てもらったわ
And so, they've both come as helpers for Fuyu and me!
ドーラあなたはファイアードレイクだそうね
Dora, you're a firedrake, right?
このヨハネの眷属として存分に暴れてもらうわよ
As a vassal of Yohane, I expect you to run wild to your heart's content!
本物の善子ちゃん
The real Yoshiko-chan!
かわいいやばいやばいヨハネ
So cute! No way, no way! Yohane!
ごめんなさいでも今日はヨハネと共演できて本当に光栄です
I'm sorry, but it's truly an honor to co-star with Yohane today!
ヨハネの眷属としてファイアードレイクのドーラ馳せ参じました！
As a vassal of Yohane, I, Dora the firedrake, have arrived!
今日はよろしくお願いします！
I look forward to working with you today!
冬優子たちのアンバサダーはラプラスちゃんだです
Fuyu and the others' ambassador is Laplace-chan!
とってもかわいいラプラスちゃんよろしくね
She's so cute! Nice to meet you, Laplace-chan!
ラプ様だよ
It's Lord Lap!
今回のコラボで冬優子のこともっと好きになっちゃったぞ
This collaboration made me like Fuyu even more!
貴様らもこんなコラボめったに見ることができないからありがたく思えよ
You guys better be grateful, since you rarely see a collab like this!
メンバー紹介も終わったところで今回は歌合戦にちなんでメンバーが分かれているんだけどせっかくだし今日だけのチーム名をつけてみない？
Now that member introductions are done, since this is inspired by a song battle, the members are split up. Since we have the chance, why don't we give ourselves a one-day-only team name?
いいですね歌合戦番組っぽくなってきたぞ
That sounds great! It's starting to feel like a real song battle show!
うーんチーム名何がいいかな
Hmm, what team name would be good?
ドレイクたち結構名前の一部分をくっつけてチーム名を決めることが多いんですけど
We drakes often decide our team names by sticking parts of our names together, but...
善子ちゃん善子ちゃんとドーラだからヨッシーラとか？
Yoshiko-chan... since it's Yoshiko-chan and Dora, how about Yoshira?
ヨハネ！それにめちゃくちゃダサイ！
Yohane! And that's super lame!
いやださいな
Yeah, super lame...
冬優とってもかわいいと思うな
Fuyu thinks it's super cute, though!
絶対ダメよ
Absolutely not!
それじゃあ私が直々に決めてあげるリトルデーモン達もよく聞きなさい
Then I will decide it myself! Listen well, Little Demons!
そうねヨハドラよ
Let's see... Yohadra!
うーん少しだけ変わったかな
Hmm... Is it just a little weird?
あれ結構いいと思ったんだけどな
Huh, I thought it was pretty good...
私ヨハネの発言は絶対なんだからもうこれに決まりよ
Whatever I, Yohane, say is absolute, so this is it!
ドーラいいわよね
Dora, that's fine with you, right?
はいヨハネがそう言うなら大丈夫です
Yes, if Yohane says so, it's fine!
よろし。それではそちらはどうするの？
Good. Now, what about you guys?
2人の名前の最初の2文字をとってふゆラブなんてどうかな
How about taking the first two letters of our names to make "FuyuLove"?
まあそのまま過ぎるけど冬優子がいいならいっか
Well, it's a bit too straightforward, but if Fuyu likes it, I guess it's fine.
うれしー
Yay!
ありがとう
Thank you
よし！
All right!
それじゃあ名前も決まったところで番組を始めていくわよ！
Now that we've decided on a name, let's start the show!
全国のリスナーデモンたち 私たちの音楽に 酔いしれなさい！
Listeners all across the nation, lose yourselves in our music!
Can you feel “Madness” この世界の全て
Can you feel "Madness"? Everything in this world...
Can you feel “Galaxy” 果てを飛び越えた Glory
Can you feel "Galaxy"? Glory that leaps beyond the bounds...
バイアスかかるパイプスで 深淵より宿すパワーを tune up
Tune up the power born from the abyss with biased pipes!
Massで成り立つCapitalに 一罰百戒 穿つ「理想像」
Piercing the "ideal" with harsh example upon Capital built on mass!
傷天害理 汝、二乗で満たす存在意義
Reason for existence filled with doubled harm to heaven and earth!
In the Flow 直な「ない」返し「はい」 獅子搏兎 ＋ Impact!
In the Flow: direct "no", returning "yes", hunting a rabbit with full force + Impact!
まわりまわる多様性を 感情的なルールで縛り付け「うるせぇ全く！」
Binding the revolving diversity with emotional rules, "Shut up, seriously!"
うなりうなる可能性で 全て超えた Identity
Identity that leaps beyond everything with howling, writhing potential!
Can you feel my soul
Baby, up & up now 3,2,1
Nothing bad happened.
案じたってまわる 循環定義
Circular definition that revolves no matter how much you worry
変わらぬ真理 合縁奇縁の泥み点
Unchanging truth, the muddy point of strange affinity and ties
make it Nothing bad happened.
君は君 いらぬ疑心暗鬼
You are you, unneeded paranoia
不毛なBlowと焦らすFlow 募る鼓動でHigh up & up
Fruitless Blow and teasing Flow, high up & up with gathering beats
我が道をゆくMinority あざとくIrony
Minority going my own way, cunningly Irony
ちりり見せるピュアなハート 悩殺御免
Showing a flickering pure heart, captivating by all means
夢描いてた名声赫赫 人類学 核にtuning up
Brilliant fame I dreamed of, tuning up to the core of anthropology
すべて解き明かす 心 満たす様
Unravelling everything, the way it satisfies the heart
その美的知識を刺激して 私的に生きてる体も shaking up and shape up
Stimulating that aesthetic knowledge, shaking up and shape up even the body living selfishly
我が道をゆく共犯者
Accomplice going my own way
Are you ready to fall into deep.
かすむ視界は冥々 びく名声 叫べ「メーデー」
Hazy vision is dark and dim, ringing fame, shout "Mayday"
無垢な犠牲 足りない愛を狂わす
Innocent sacrifice, driving the lacking love mad
まわりまわる多様性を 感情的なルールで縛り付け「うるせぇ全く！」
Binding the revolving diversity with emotional rules, "Shut up, seriously!"
うなりうなる可能性で 全て超えた Identity
Identity that leaps beyond everything with howling, writhing potential!
キミにfall in love 恋のSOS ずっと胸が苦しいんです
Fall in love with you, love's SOS, my chest has been hurting the whole time.
ハヤクRescue 「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて！
Hurry, Rescue! Quickly notice the telepathy of "I like you"!
初めて出逢ったときから ハートが震えてたんだよ
From the moment we first met, my heart has been trembling.
無意識に 意識しちゃう この感じはきっと(重症です)
Unconsciously becoming aware of you, this feeling is surely (a severe condition).
目と目合うだけで 顔が熱いのかなし 話しかけられて 頭がパニック
Just locking eyes makes my face hot, being spoken to makes my head panic.
ドキドキし過ぎて会話続かない
My heart races so much, I can't keep a conversation going.
どうすればいいの? こんな気持ちを
What should I do with feelings like these?
(キミとの相性診断) 星占いなら So good, So good
(Our compatibility diagnosis) If it's astrology, So good, So good
(トモダチなんかじゃないよ) ときめいてる
((We're not just friends, you know) I'm fluttering with excitement)
キミに Fall in love 恋の SOS
Fall in love with you, love's SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My chest has been aching the whole time
ハヤク Rescue 「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて!
Hurry, Rescue! Quick, realize the telepathy of "I like you"!
これは Fall in love 恋の SOS
This is Fall in love, love's SOS
もっとキミに近づきたい
I want to get closer to you
終わらせて 片想い My heart 全部抱きしめて
End this unrequited love, My heart, hold it all close
キミが好きな音楽や 映画のことリサーチして
Researching the music and movies you like
SNS見るたびに イイネ押すの (アピールだよ)
Every time I check SNS, I like your posts (it's an appeal)
四六時中キミのこと考えて 妄想しながら枕ギュッてした
Thinking about you 24/7, hugging my pillow while daydreaming
明日はどんな服装でいこうかな
What kind of outfit should I wear tomorrow?
キミ想うだけでなんか照れる
Just thinking about you makes me somehow shy
(キミの名前を呼べば) ただそれだけでも Dreaming, Dreaming
(If I call your name) Even just that is Dreaming, Dreaming
(溺れそうな私を) 助け出して
(Rescue me, who looks like I'm drowning))
キミに Fall in love 恋の SOS
Fall in love with you, love's SOS
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
My chest has been aching the whole time
ハヤク Rescue 「好き」のテレパシーに早く気づいて!
Hurry, Rescue! Quick, realize the telepathy of "I like you"!
これは Fall in love 恋の SOS
This is Fall in love, love's SOS
もっとキミに近づきたい
I want to get closer to you
終わらせて 片想い My heart 全部抱きしめて
End this unrequited love, My heart, hold it all close
はーーい！
Hi there!
というわけで それぞれの楽曲を交換して歌ってみましたーー！
So, we exchanged our songs and tried singing them!
冬優子の「合縁奇縁」 めちゃくちゃかっこよかった！
Fuyuko's "Aien Kien" was super cool!
この曲のラップめっちゃ難しいのに ちゃんと言えててすげぇ！ さすがアイドルだなぁ
The rap in this song is super difficult, but you said it properly, amazing! As expected of an idol.
ありがとう！ ラブちゃんの「SOS」 とっても可愛かったよ！
Thank you! Rabu-chan's "SOS" was super cute!
歌ってもらえて嬉しいな
I'm so happy you sang it.
それじゃ最後に みんなにもう1曲だけ聴いてもらっちゃおうかな
Well then, finally, shall we have everyone listen to just one more song?
この曲大好き！
I love this song!
いつか歌ってみたかったから 冬優子と歌えるなんて めっちゃ嬉しい！
I've always wanted to sing it someday, so being able to sing it with Fuyuko makes me so happy!
ふゆ嬉しい！ ラブちゃんだいすき！
Fuyu is so happy! I love Rabu-chan!
ふゆこ 頑張ってるな
Fuyuko is trying hard.
それでは聴いてください
Now then, please listen.
Wandering Dream Chaser
闇を切り刻むように 昂ぶる思い
Emotions surging as if slicing through the darkness
乱反射 To the stage 見せつけるわ
Diffuse reflection To the stage, I'll show you
目指すものがあるから 心に迷いなんてないの
Because I have a goal, there's no hesitation in my heart
どんな試練があっても Going my ray
No matter what trials come, Going my ray
誰かが作った道を (Dash!)
The path someone else made (Dash!)
追い越しした その上で (Breakout!)
Beyond overtaking it (Breakout!)
胸に滾る夢を この手でつかむの
Grasping the boiling dream in my chest with these hands
胸に、滾る夢を この手でつかむの
Grasping the surging dreams in my chest with my own hands
諦めない、絶対
I'll never give up, absolutely not.
高く高い壁だって Get Chance & Luck 飛び越え
Even a towering wall, I'll leap over with get chance & luck!
異彩の光で魅せるわ
Showing you with a unique brilliance.
憧れいつの日か Grow up & Change 突き抜け
Someday my yearning will grow up & change, breaking through!
私たちが目指す Goalへ導く (Dance with the shine)
Guiding us to the goal we aim for (Dance with the shine)
Day after day 彷徨っても 辿り着く
Day after day, even if I wander, I'll arrive.
高鳴る鼓動が鳴り響いてる
The beating pulse echoes resoundingly.
Wandering Dream Chaser
時代を巻き込むくらい ぶち抜く Crazy
Crazy enough to sweep through the era.
強引な Naked heart さらけ出すよ
Baring my pushy, naked heart.
中途半端じゃなくて 思いのままに暴れたい
Not half-heartedly, I want to rage just as I feel.
失うものがあっても We'll be alright
Even if I lose something, we'll be alright.
歪んだ光だって (Bright!) 重なり研ぎ澄まされ (Be one!)
Even distorted light (Bright!) overlaps and is honed (Be one!)
未来 照らしだせる チカラになるから
Because it becomes the power to illuminate the future.
永い長い道だって Don't stop & back 駆け抜け
Even a long, long road, don't stop & back, run through!
新たな世界を拓くよ
Paving the way to a new world.
想いを重ねるほど Heat up & Chain 輝き
The more feelings overlap, heat up & chain, shining brightly.
私たちの スピード上げていくから (Step up my heart)
Raising our speed going forward (Step up my heart)
We just trying 変えていく 変わってく
We just trying, changing, transforming.
描いた理想を叶えていく
Making the ideals we drew come true.
Wandering Dream Chaser
高く高い壁だって Get Chance & Luck 飛び越え
Even a towering wall, I'll leap over with get chance & luck!
異彩の光で魅せるわ
Showing you with a unique brilliance.
憧れいつの日か Grow up & Change 突き抜け
Someday my yearning will grow up & change, breaking through!
私たちが目指す Goalへ導く (Dance with the shine)
Guiding us to the goal we aim for (Dance with the shine)
Day after day 彷徨っても 辿り着く
Day after day, even if I wander, I'll arrive.
高鳴る鼓動が鳴り響いてる
The beating pulse echoes resoundingly.
Wandering Dream Chaser
際限の無い厄災にさえ 黄金を踏み散らすのは誰！
Who is it that tramples over gold even in endless disaster?!
揺れる黒の狂鳴と 禍つ闇のサイレンと
With the swaying black dissonance and ominous darkness's siren,
Ruleを知らない blood エンドバッドさ 暴力
Blood that knows no rules, end-bad style, violence!
“ニンゲン”をかたる魔獣の声
The voice of a beast pretending to be "human".
宝ヲ奪ウ者達のcall 焔ト荒ラス者達のgrowl
The call of pillagers, the growl of desolators.
Ruleを知らない blood エンドバッドさ 暴力
Blood that knows no rules, end-bad style, violence!
黄金を踏み散らす奴は誰！
Who is the one trampling over gold?!
終末を嗤う絶望も
Even despair that mocks the end,
明日を見据えるReloadも ‐喰らう覚悟はあるか？
Even Reload gazing at tomorrow—do you have the resolve to devour it?
有るのは虹の夢 或いは紅き翅 はじめようか
What remains is a rainbow dream, or crimson wings. Shall we begin?
the 咆哮！ wo wo wo
The roar! Wo wo wo...
燃やしてやろうじゃないか 有象無象 全て！
Let's burn it all down, every last commonplace existence!
wo wo wo
研ぎ澄まされた理不尽さえ 呑み込んで
Swallowing even honed unreasonableness,
傷ついたって 毀れたって 護りたい “共火”がある世界！
Hurt or shattered, I want to protect the world with "shared fire"!
上等 サア
Bring it on, now!
今夜も熱くやろうじゃないか 灼熱ノRed Ruler
Let's do it hot again tonight, scorching Red Ruler!
宝ヲ奪ウ者達のcall
The call of those who steal treasures,
焔ト荒ラス者達のgrowl
the growl of those who burn and pillage,
終わりを知らないblood エンドバッドさ 暴力
blood that knows no end, an end-bad violence!
光の裏側で笑う不浄理！
Absurdity laughing in the shadows of light!
灯閉ざす雨の音も 静寂に仇すクロウも
The sound of rain closing out the light, crows defying silence,
静寂にあたなす衣も
and garments defying the quiet—
一刃向かう覚悟はあるか？
do you have the resolve to face the blade?
ヒトツはヒトの夢 フタツの不確か・生
One is a human dream, two are uncertain lives.
はじめようか
Shall we begin?
the 咆哮！
The roar!
wo wo wo
どうかしてやろうじゃないか 有象無象 全て！
Shall we mess with everything in this chaotic world?!
どうかしてやろうじゃないか 奪う者
Shall we mess with those who steal?!
焦がしてやろうじゃないか 有象無象 全て！
Shall we scorch everything in this chaotic world?!
その先にある闇さえ 呑み込んで！
Swallowing even the darkness that lies beyond!
傷ついたって 壊れたって 護りたい
Even if hurt, even if broken, I want to protect
“共火”があるんだ 上等 サア
the "shared flame" we have. Bring it on!
今夜も熱くやろうじゃないか 灼熱ノRedRuler
Shall we heat things up tonight too, scorching Red Ruler?
ヒトはヒトツの存在とは限らない
Humans are not necessarily a singular existence.
white wing black wing
昨日と違う私が 違う答え出してたんだ
Yesterday's me and today's me arrived at different answers.
noがyesなら yesはno? どっちも気分次第
If no is yes, is yes no? Whichever I feel like!
Ah きっと知らない自分が もっといるの
Ah, there must be more of me I don't yet know.
この退屈セカイを渡るには
To cross this tedious world,
力合わせなきゃ駄目よ
we have to join forces.
ほら私と貴方とワタシなら やがて奇跡が起きちゃうって！
Look, if it's me, you, and me, miracles are bound to happen!
だけど今は我慢しようか 雌伏の時さ unstable world
But for now, let's hold back—it's a time of waiting, unstable world.
ヒトは記憶でヒトだと信じ込んで
Humans firmly believe they are human through memory,
good deed bad deed
真の姿がみんなと違うことを 嫌悪して
loathing the fact that our true form differs from everyone else's.
goはgoだよ stopじゃない さあ迷わず飛んじゃえば
Go is go, not stop—so fly without hesitation!
nonstop and flyだよ stopじゃない さあ迷わず飛んじゃえば
It's nonstop and fly, not stop—so fly without hesitation!
Ah 本当の自分わかるんだって 本当さ
Ah, you'll find your true self, really!
まだ聖なるセカイ夢見てるの？
Are you still dreaming of a holy world?
美しさは脆いものよ
Beauty is a fragile thing.
たぶん貴方とアナタと私達 無垢なままでいられない
Perhaps you, you, and us can never remain innocent.
Fallen Angel
ファイヤードレイク！
firedrake!
感じます……精霊結界の損壊により魔力構造が変化していくのが
I feel it... As the spirit barrier is damaged, the magical structure is changing,
かの約束の地で出会った堕天使ヨハネの声により
through the voice of Yoshiko the fallen angel whom I met in that promised land,
ワシが遂に目を覚ますのですの！
I finally awaken!
全てのリトルデーモンに捧げる
Dedicated to all little demons!
Dedicating this to all the little demons!
堕天の力を！
The power of a fallen angel!
聖なるセカイ夢見てるの？
Are you dreaming of a holy world?
白い翼を背にしたいの？
Do you want white wings on your back?
でも貴方とアナタと私達 無垢なままでいられない
But you, you, and us cannot remain innocent.
この退屈セカイを渡るには
To cross this boring world,
力を合わせなきゃ駄目よ
we have to join forces.
ほら私と貴方とワタシなら やがて奇跡が起きちゃうって！
Look, if you, me, and I come together, a miracle will happen!
だけど今は我慢しようか 雌伏の時 タイミング待ってる
But for now, let's hold back and wait for our time.
いつかどこか私と貴方 出会う筈でしょ unstable world
Someday, somewhere, you and I are bound to meet, an unstable world.
皆さんどうでしたかー！
Everyone, how was it?!
私たちヨハドラチームも お互いの曲をカバーさせてもらいました！
Our Yohadora team got to cover each other's songs too!
ドーラよかったわ！ とっても新鮮だった！
Dora, that was great! It felt so fresh!
でもあなたの曲も難しかった…
But your song was difficult too...
ありがとうございます！ ヨハネの曲が歌えて めちゃくちゃ楽しかったです！
Thank you so much! It was so much fun to sing Yohane's song!
そう、ドーラのこのレッドルーラーめちゃめちゃ難しいんですけど ヨハネ完璧に歌い上げてて聴き惚れちゃいました さすがです！
Right? Dora's Red Ruler is super hard, but Yohane sang it so perfectly I was mesmerized. Amazing!
でもドーラ この程度でリトルデーモンは満足しないわ
But Dora, little demons won't be satisfied with just this.
はい、その通り！
Yes, exactly!
さあ、私たちの歌声に酔いしれなさい！ それでは聞いてください！
Now, be enchanted by our singing voices! And now, listen to this!
Strawberry Trapper
Ready?
待ってないよ…LOVE!!
I won't wait for love!
見つけた！ キミは淋しい瞳だった
I found you! You had such lonely eyes.
鼓動が鳴ってる「手に入れなさい」と
Your heartbeat's calling out, "Take me in your arms."
冷静なほど 熱さを楽しめるの
The calmer you are, the more you enjoy the heat.
高まる想いは抑えて
Hold back those mounting feelings,
静かに 集めるキミの情報
and quietly gather information on you.
確かに 価値ある Sensitive mind
A truly valuable, sensitive mind.
背後に歩み寄る スリルがたまらない
Stepping up from behind, the thrill is irresistible.
狙い定めたら 逃がさないから
Once I take aim, I won't let you escape.
逃がさないから My target!!
I won't let you escape, my target!
(Trap in dice) 恋の罠から
(Trap in dice) From love's trap,
(Trap in night) 始まりたい
(Trap in night) I want to start.
(Trap in heart) 踊りながら人生のルーレット
(Trap in heart) Dancing through life's roulette.
(運命は) ありきたりじゃつまらない
(It is fate) Cliché love is so boring.
特別を感じたいの 奪いたいキミのこと
I want to feel something special, I want to steal you away.
待ってないよ…LOVE!!
I won't wait for love!
怯える顔が 見たいのなんてさ
Wanting to see your frightened face...
企むときは きっとワルイ顔ね
When scheming, you surely have a wicked look.
いただきたいのは その心よ
What I want to take is your heart.
脆くて 危うい優しさ
Fragile and precarious kindness.
静かな 孤独を愛するキミ
You, who love quiet solitude.
確かな 輝き放つの
Emit a certain radiance.
気づかれたくない うちに 私のモノにしたい
Before you notice, I want to make you mine.
狙い定めたよ 逃がさないから
Once I take aim, I won't let you escape.
逃がさないから My target!!
I won't let you escape, my target!
(Trick in dice) 恋に賭けたら
(Trick in dice) Wagered on love,
(Trick in night) 後に引けない
(Trick in night) No turning back.
(Trick in heart) 勝つだけでしょ人生はルーレット
(Trick in heart) Just win, it's life's roulette.
(運命と)わかる出会い素敵だわ
(It's fate) An encounter you know is wonderful.
特別を感じたら 「手に入れて」
Once you feel special, "take it in your hands."
秘めたる声は berry の香り Trap in one night
A secret voice with a berry scent, trap in one night.
赤い berry 甘く強く 滴って
A red berry, dripping sweet and strong.
(Trick in Dice) 恋に賭けたら
(Trick in Dice) If you bet on love,
(Trick in Night) 後に引けない
(Trick in Night) there's no turning back.
(Trick in Heart) 勝つだけでしょ人生はルーレット
(Trick in Heart) Winning is everything, life's a roulette.
(Trap in Dice) 恋の罠から
(Trap in Dice) From the trap of love,
(Trap in Night) 始まりたい
(Trap in Night) I want it to begin.
(Trap in Heart) 踊りながら人生のルーレット
(Trap in Heart) Dancing along to life's roulette,
(運命は) ありきたりじゃつまらない
(Destiny) shouldn't be so ordinary.
特別を感じたいの 奪いたいキミのこと
I want to feel special, I want to take you away.
待ってないよ 甘い甘いberry
I won't wait, sweet, sweet berry.
心に赤の誘惑 Berry Trapper 狙い定めたよ
The red temptation in my heart, Berry Trapper, I've locked onto you!
というわけで冬たちのコラボ歌謡曲を聞いてもらったんですが
So, you've listened to the collaboration songs of the winter idols,
みんなはどうだった？
how did everyone find it?
最高だったわ！
It was amazing!
本当に一緒に歌えたんだな…
I really got to sing together with everyone...
ああ 夢みたい まだ現実とは思えない
Ah, it's like a dream, I still can't believe it's real.
なんだかまだリトルデーモン達が満足していないよね
Somehow, the Little Demons still aren't satisfied, right?
仕方ないわね
It can't be helped,
特別にもっとこの世を揺るがす 異次元なコラボを魅せてあげる
so specially, we'll show you an otherworldly collaboration that will shake the world even more!
みんなで練習してきたもんね
We've all been practicing hard for this, after all.
さあさあ！
Come on, come on!
もっと虜にしちゃいます
We'll captivate you even more!
みんな 準備はいい？
Everyone, are you ready?
それでは聞いてください
Now then, please listen to this:
異次元★♥BIGBANG
Chojigen ★♥ BIGBANG!
Wow wow 目指す場所まで
Wow wow, to the place we aim for
Wow wow 一緒に見に行こう
Wow wow, let's go see it together
L! O! I! L! L! O! I! L!
Yes! 最高の巡り合いだね
Yes! It's the best encounter,
交わるはずのない Heart & Voice
a Heart & Voice that shouldn't intersect.
夢と声と夢が 重なってく この瞬間 (oh yes!)
Dreams, voices, and dreams overlapping at this moment (oh yes!)
断然胸が熱くなるよ
My chest definitely gets warmer.
超絶！怒涛 Showtime へおいで
Come to the super intense, surging Showtime!
愛と！ LOVE愛が ここにあって きみがいる
Love and LOVE are right here, and you are here.
叶わないこと なんてないから
Because nothing is impossible,
叶えにゆこう ぎゅっと 手を握ったら 勇気みなぎる
let's make it come true, if we hold hands tightly, courage overflows.
美しく咲く花の様に 僕らの言葉がいま 照らし出してく 優しく強くこの歌で
Like beautifully blooming flowers, our words now illuminate us, gently and strongly with this song.
この世界中 包み込んで 離さないよ
Wrapping around this world, never letting you go,
約束するからさ ついてきて！
I promise, so follow us!
千年の星から 光が集まって ひとつになって みんなの色 あわせたらBeautiful!
Lights gathering from a thousand stars, becoming one, combining all our colors makes it Beautiful!
ずっと消えないで 未来まで 永遠に続くメロディアス もっと(もっと)遠く
Never fading away until the future, a melody that continues eternally, further and further away,
飛べる気がするんだよ to you
I feel like I can fly to you.
Wow wow 目指す場所まで (知りたい？)
Wow wow, to the place we aim for (Want to know?)
Wow wow 一緒に見に行こう
Wow wow, let's go see it together.
感動的な旅にしようよ 人生はまさにKiss & Cry
Let's make it a touching journey, life is truly Kiss & Cry.
明日今日も何が起こるなんて サプライズ
Tomorrow and today, whatever happens is a surprise.
嬉しいことも 楽しいことも 全部あげたい
Happy things, fun things, I want to give you all of them.
うんと 手を伸ばしたら 誰かに届く
If we stretch out our hands wide, it will reach someone.
刻んで歴史の上に 僕らは歩いてきた 可能性ってさ 有限じゃない 無限大だ (∞だ) Infinityだ
Engraving upon history, we have walked on, possibility isn't finite, it's infinite, (it's infinity), it's Infinity!
塗り替えてく 新しいページ まだまだ止まらない ついてきて！！
Repainting new pages, still unstoppable, follow us!!
異次元のチカラで ドキドキ高まって
With dimensional power, my heart races with excitement,
どこまでだって いけるかもって
thinking I can go anywhere,
溢れ出したCurious! ずっと忘れない 未来まで
overflowing with Curious! Never forgetting until the future.
この景色はメモリアル 一瞬だって 宝物みたいだよ…for me
This scenery is a memorial, even a single second is like a treasure... for me.
ラララララ
Lalalalala...
大切にしよう
Let's cherish it
愛をこめて歌おう
and sing with love.
どんどん大きくなってゆく輪
The circle that keeps growing larger,
踊る踊る 新しい風 ねぇこんなはじめての予感
dancing, dancing, new wind. Hey, such a first premonition,
奇跡みたい…!
like a miracle...!
L!O!L! L!O!L!
幾億の星から 光が集まって
Lights gathered from billions of stars,
ひとつになって みんなの色
becoming one, everyone's colors.
あわせたら超Beautiful!!! ずっと消えないで 未来まで
Combined, super Beautiful!!! Never fade away until the future.
永遠に続くメロディアス もっと遠く
Melodias continuing forever, further and further,
飛べる気がするんだよ…to you
I feel like I can fly... to you.
Wow wow 大好きだって叫びたい
Wow wow I want to shout that I love you,
Wow wow きみと、きみとに伝えたい
Wow wow I want to tell you, you, and you.
Wow wow 眩しい眩しい 目指す場所まで
Wow wow to the dazzling, dazzling place we aim for,
一緒に見に行こう
let's go see it together.
異次元フェスのために作られた楽曲「異次元♥BIGBANG」を披露させていただいたわ！
We performed "Ijigen♥BIGBANG", a song created for Ijigen Fes!
この曲で一つになれた感じがしたね
It felt like we became one with this song, right?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いやあ、こんな舞台でこの4人で歌えるなんて…最後泣きそうだった…
Man, to be able to sing with these four on such a stage... I almost cried at the end...
冬優たちにとっても 見てくれてるみんなにとっても 貴重な時間になったんじゃないかなって思います
I think it became a precious time both for us Fuyuko and for everyone watching.
ね？
Right?
そうね。でもこれは前夜祭みたいなもの。
That's right. But this is like an eve festival.
本番は明日よ！
The main event is tomorrow!
私たちを含めたくさんのアイドルが切磋琢磨するライブが遂に開催されるのだから！
Because a live where many idols, including us, compete and hone their skills is finally going to be held!
って、めちゃくちゃ楽しみだね！見てくれたみんな 冬優の虜にしちゃいます
And man, I'm super excited! Everyone who watched, we're going to make you Fuyuko's captives!
望むところよ！
Bring it on!
ラプちゃんもドーラちゃんも明日からのイベント応援してくれるんだよね？意気込み聞いちゃってもいいかな？
Lap-chan and Dora-chan, you're cheering us on for the event starting tomorrow, right? Can we hear your enthusiasm?
アンバサダーとして頑張ってきたけどついに本番だ！もうただのオタクとして楽しむぞ！プロデューサーも一緒に盛り上がろう！
I've worked hard as an ambassador, but it's finally the main event! I'm going to enjoy it just as an otaku! Producers, let's get hyped together!
アンバサダーのお話をいただいてからあっという間にライブもう明日！まだちょっと心がソワソワしていますが
Ever since receiving the talk about being ambassadors, time flew and the live is already tomorrow! My heart is still fluttering a bit, but
スクールアイドルを応援する皆さん！声出しの準備はできていますか？もう明日ですよ！一緒に楽しみましょう！
everyone supporting school idols! Are you ready to use your voices? It's already tomorrow! Let's enjoy it together!
はぁ〜ありがとうございました！明日からもよろしくね！
Haah~ Thank you very much! Please treat us well tomorrow too!
というわけでそろそろ番組も終わりなんだけど最後に明日からのライブの告知をアンバサダーの二人からお願いするわね！
With that said, the program is almost ending, so finally we'd like the two ambassadors to make the announcement for tomorrow's live!
はい！異次元フェス DAY1は明日12月9日(土)開演17:00 場所は東京ドーム
Yes! Ijigen Fes DAY1 is tomorrow, December 9th (Sat) start 17:00 at Tokyo Dome!
総勢100名以上のアイドルとメンバーたちのパフォーマンス絶対に聞き逃せません！
The performances of over 100 idols and members total definitely cannot be missed!
みんな準備は万端？
Is everyone fully prepared?
忘れものはない？Tシャツよし！マフラータオルよし！チケットよし！
No forgotten items? T-shirt check! Muffler towel check! Ticket check!
買いそびれちゃったグッズは会場物販もあるからぜひぜひチェックしてください！
For goods you missed buying, there's venue merchandise sales too, so please be sure to check them out!
アイドルマスター ラブライブ！ブレード、ドレイクも買いました！
I bought the Idolmaster Love Live! Blade and Drake too!
明日あさって、思いっぴい特別な時間を楽しみましょう！
Tomorrow and the day after, let's enjoy a specially passionate time to the fullest!
じゃ、観客席で会おうな。隣にいるかもよ。
Well then, let's meet in the audience seats. I might be right next to you.
そしてあそびステージさんとABEMAさんで配信されるから現地のひとも配信で見てるひとも一緒に見ようね！めっちゃくちゃたくさん曲やるらしいから楽しみだ！
And since it'll be streamed on Asobi Stage and ABEMA, whether you're at the venue or watching the stream, let's watch together! They're doing tons of songs so I'm super excited!
ライブでも見返せるから、絶対何回も見るぞ！
You can replay the live, so be sure to watch it over and over!
今日、この番組を見て、ちょっとでもいいなって思ってもらえたら、
If you watched this program today and thought it was even a little good,
配信で絶対、絶対見てほしいなっ！
I definitely, definitely want you to watch the stream!
ふゆ、待ってますね♥
Fuyu will be waiting for you♥
そうね。絶対に後悔させないライブを披露して、
That's right. Delivering a live performance you won't regret,
会場すべてを、いえ、全世界を魅了してみせるわ。
and charming the entire venue—no, the entire world.
じゃあ最後に、今日の感想をひとことずつ。まずはおふゆから！
Now, lastly, a word about your thoughts today. First from Fuyu!
今日はグループやユニットの壁を越えて、歌で繋がれた感じがして、とっても楽しかったです♥
Today, transcending the walls of groups and units, it felt like we were connected through song, and I had so much fun♥
今日番組を見てくれたみんなも、そう思ってもらえてると、ふゆ嬉しいです！
If everyone who watched the program today feels the same way, Fuyu is so happy!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
じゃあ次はラプちゃん！はい！今日は最後まで観てくれて、本当にありがとうございます！
Next is Laplus-chan! Yes! Thank you so much for watching until the end today!
ただの一般プロデューサーだったのに、気づいたらここにいました…
I was just an ordinary producer, but before I knew it, I was here...
本当に本当に嬉しいし、今日は正直緊張しました！自我を保てないかと思いました…
I'm truly, truly happy, and to be honest, I was so nervous today! I thought I wouldn't be able to keep my sanity...
大好きな冬優子と大好きなアイマスの楽曲を歌えて、本当に嬉しかったぞ！
Singing songs by Fuyu-chan, whom I love, and iM@S, whom I love, made me so happy!
本当にありがとうございます、本当にありがとうございます！これからもVTuberというよりかはプロデューサーが本職なので精進していきたいと思います！
Thank you so much, thank you so much! From now on, since my main job is a producer rather than a VTuber, I want to keep devoting myself!
ごめんなさい、うちの社長ー！
I'm sorry, our president!
じゃあ次、ドーラ！ふふふっ、改めまして、ラブライブ！アンバサダーを務めさせていただきましたドーラです！
Next is Dora! Fufuffu, once again, I'm Dora, serving as the Love Live! Ambassador!
いや本当に、これが前夜祭なのか!?というくらいめちゃめちゃ楽しかったです！
Honestly, it was so much fun that I wondered if this was really just a pre-event!
今日こんなに楽しかったら、明日はどうになっちゃうの!?と怯えてます。
If today was this fun, I'm terrified of what tomorrow will be like.
本当にラブライブ！のこと、そしてスクールアイドルみんなのことを好きでいてよかったなと思いました。
I really thought it was great that I've loved Love Live! and all the school idols.
みんなが知っていてドーラが知らないラブライブ！の魅力もきっとまだまだあると思います。
I'm sure there are still many charms of Love Live! that everyone knows but Dora doesn't.
もっともっと応援して、もっともっと大好きになっていけたらなと思っております。
I hope to support them more and more, and come to love them even more.
こんな素敵な機会をくださって本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you truly so much for giving me such a wonderful opportunity!
冬優子ちゃんとラプ様、そしてヨハネと歌えたこと誇りに生きていきます。
I will live proudly in having sung with Fuyu-chan, Lapu-sama, and Yohane.
これでヨハネの魅力もみんなに伝わって、今頃堕天しまくりなはず！
With this, Yohane's charm should have reached everyone, and by now everyone must be falling into depravity like crazy!
全国のすべての人間が闇の力にひれ伏し堕天する姿が見られて、このヨハネも気分がいいわ。
Seeing all human beings across the country prostrate before the power of darkness and fall into depravity puts this Yohane in a good mood too.
明日もまた会場をリトルデーモンたちで埋め尽くして、このヨハネ様の歌声にひれ伏すことは定められた運命…
Tomorrow too, filling the venue with Little Demons and prostrating to this Yohane-sama's singing voice is a decreed destiny...
それじゃあ名残惜しいけど今日はこれで おしまい。明日約束の地、東京ドームで会いましょう！
Well then, it's bittersweet, but that's it for today. Let's meet tomorrow at the promised land, Tokyo Dome!
それでは、せーの！ありがとうございました！
Now then, ready, go! Thank you very much!